Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010 TJU.2010.01.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Press Office, 1981-2005; IV.
  - Press Releases, 1981-2005; 1.
    - August-December 1993 (Box 1223, Folder 10)
      - Senator Specter's resolution calling on UN to expedite prosecution of war criminals in former Yugoslavia is passed by the Senate, August 5, 1993; 3.
      - Statement by Senator Specter in opposition to President Clinton's budget package, August 6, 1993; 4.
      - Senator Specter to hold media availability tomorrow, Tuesday, August 31, following meeting with state and city officials and community activists on health needs of low-income households, August 30, 1993; 5.
      - Senator Specter to be in Pittsburgh on Tuesday, September 7, to visit and tour the Breast Care Center at Magee Women's Hospital, September 7, 1993; 6.
      - Senator Specter joins Senator Sasser in introducing legislation to create a police corps. program, September 10, 1993; 7.
      - Reaction of Senator Specter on Israeli-PLO agreement, September 10, 1993; 8.
      - Senator Specter reacts to Israel-PLO peace treaty, September 13, 1993; 9.
      - Senate approves Specter amendments for DOD to improve base closure cost estimates and to consult workers and others in base redevelopment and closure plans, September 14, 1993; 10.
      - Statement by Senator Arlen Specter on GOP's health reform plan, September, 1993; 11.
      - Senator Specter pledges support to PA cities and rural areas seeking designation as empowerment zones and enterprise communities, September 17, 1993; 12.
      - Senators Specter and Wofford request National Guard training flights over northcentral Pennsylvania parks be suspended, September 17, 1993; 13.
      - Senator Specter to tour breast and prostate cancer screening areas at University of Pennsylvania hospital on Monday, September 20, September 20, 1993; 14.
      - Senator Specter announces $12.5 million federal grant to Pennsylvania for a breast and cervical cancer early detection program, September 20, 1993; 15.
      - Senator Specter comments on President Clinton's health plan, September 22, 1993; 16.
      - Senate Appropriations Committee funds Pennsylvania water projects advocated by Senator Specter, September 23, 1993; 17.
      - Senator Specter to be in Harrisburg on Monday, September 27, to hold an open house/town hall meeting on health care reform; will also endorse GOP candidates for two state court posts, September 27, 1993; 18.
      - Statement by Senator Specter on Somalia situation, October 5, 1993; 19.
      - Senator Specter raises concern about bureaucracy created by the Clinton health care proposal n chart outlining the proposed new and expanded entities, October 8, 1993; 20.
      - Specter-Wofford amendment, passed by the Senate, would prohibit air national guard from spending funds for combat training over central Pennsylvania, October 14, 1993; 21.
      - Senator Specter to endorse Republican candidates for state judicial offices at press conferences tomorrow, Friday, October 15, in Delaware, Chester, and Montgomery Counties, October 14, 1993; 22.
      - Senator Specter to meet with U.S. Attorney designee, current U.S. Attorney, and 10 DAs from Eastern District of PA in Philadelphia tomorrow, Friday, October 15, to push for greater federal-state cooperation in prosecuting drug dealers, October 14, 1993; 23.
      - Senator Specter challenges Amtrak's decision to reduce train service between Harrisburg and Philadelphia, October 15, 1993; 24.
      - Senator Specter challenges Navy's preference for nuclear-powered fleet with a GAO cost-comparison study on nuclear versus conventional aircraft carriers and submarines, October 15, 1993; 25.
      - Senator Specter to be in Pittsburgh on Monday, October 18, to hold an open house/town meeting on health care reform; will also endorse candidates for three state court posts and mayor of Pittsburgh, October 18, 1993; 26.
      - Senator Specter comments on decision by U.S. Supreme Court to review Philadelphia Naval Shipyard closing case, October 18, 1993; 27.
      - Senator Specter introduces bill to protect workers' rights under state law by amending provision of ERISA, October 21, 1993; 28.
      - Senator Specter to hold cable TV "town meeting" on health care reform, October 22, 1993; 29.
      - Senator Specter to discuss Clinton health reform plan with medical group in Philadelphia today, Friday, October 29, October 29, 1993; 30.
      - Senator Specter applauds Amtrak's cooperation with PA DOT to maintain Harrisburg-Philadelphia services, October 29, 1993; 31.
      - Senator Specter urges President Clinton to exercise line-item veto now to reduce deficit; says authority exists under present law, November 9, 1993; 32.
      - Senator Specter helps preserve zinc jobs in western PA, November 10, 1993; 33.
      - Senator Specter raises issue of Philadelphia vote fraud during crime bill debate; sends letters to Attorney General Reno and others requesting investigation, November 18, 1993; 34.
      - Senator Specter votes to support NAFTA, November 20, 1993; 35.
      - Senate accepts Specter's amendment to prohibit the purchase of out-of-state lottery tickets by computer; action will benefit Pennsylvania's senior citizens, November 8, 1993; 36.
      - Senator Specter gets House-Senate conferees to restore funding for R and D facility at PNSY, November 9, 1993; 37.
      - Senator Specter says he is "delighted" about Justice Department/FBI investigation into Philadelphia vote fraud; says Stinson will be ousted as a result, November 29, 1993; 38.
      - Senator Specter and Mayor Rendell issue joint statement on the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard, November 30, 1993; 39.
      - Senators Specter and Harkin request GAO study on administrative costs of Clinton health plan, November 30, 1993; 40.
      - Senator Specter to be in Pittsburgh Wednesday, December 8, to hold an open house/town meeting on health care reform, December 8, 1993; 41.
    - January-July 1994 (Box 1223, Folder 11)
      - Senator Specter will report on the road to peace in the Middle East during breakfast meeting in Pittsburgh, on Thursday, January 20, at 8:00 am, January 20, 1994; 1.
      - Senator Specter comments on nomination of William Perry to be Secretary of Defense, January 24, 1994; 2.
      - Senator Specter conducts hearings on the role private management could play in school reform, January 25, 1994; 3.
      - Senator Specter urges Senate Appropriations Committee to provide emergency funding to Pennsylvania for January quakes and cold, February 3, 1994; 4.
      - Senate approves amendment by Senator Specter to ensure that private management companies be a school reform option as part of Goals 2000, February 4, 1994; 5.
      - Senator Specter comments on CBO's budget estimates concerning President Clinton's health plan, February 8, 1994; 6.
      - Senator Specter urges FEMA to recommend Pennsylvania as a disaster area for January quakes, cold, snow, and ice, February 10, 1994; 7.
      - Senator Specter announces that Pennsylvania to receive $20.5 million in energy assistance for low-income families, February 18, 1994; 8.
      - Senator Specter give GOP response to President Clinton's weekly address, February 19, 1994; 9.
      - Senator Specter to hold cable TV "town meeting" on health care, February 21, 1994; 10.
      - Senator Arlen Specter to discuss status of lawsuit against Navy Department with workers at Philadelphia Naval Shipyard on Friday, March 4, March 4, 1994; 11.
      - Senator Specter testifies on his bill to provide ERISA exemption for state that provide prevailing rates for public works projects, March 10, 1994; 12.
      - Senator Specter announces FEMA disaster declaration for Pennsylvania; funds available for costs incurred by emergency crews and for the repair of public utilities, March 11, 1994; 13.
      - Senator Specter announces $13 million Department of Labor grant for worker retraining at the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard, March 11, 1994; 14.
      - Goals 2000 conference committee approves amendment by Senator Specter to ensure that private management companies be a school reform option, March 16, 1994; 15.
      - Senator Specter to hold cable TV "town meeting" on crime, health care, and other issues, March 21, 1994; 16.
      - Senate adopts Senator Specters amendment providing additional funding for low income energy assistance, March 24, 1994; 17.
      - Senate adopts Senator Specters amendment providing additional funding for prisoner rehabilitation, March 24, 1994; 18.
      - Senate adopts Senator Specter's amendment urging additional funding for parental care and teen pregnancy prevention, March 24, 1994; 19.
      - Senator Specter urges additional funding for LIHEAP, prisoner job training, prenatal care and other domestic programs, March 24, 1994; 20.
      - Senator Arlen Specter to visit Dauphin County Prison on Saturday, March 26, at 11 am, March 26, 1994; 21.
      - Senator Specter give a wake-up call to communities as he testifies on the siting of hazardous waste disposal facilities in Pennsylvania, March 25, 1994; 22.
      - Senator Specter to visit project rainbow at 413 West Master Street on Monday, March 28 at 9:30 am, March 28, 1994; 23.
      - Senator Specter acts to stem the flow of out-of-state waste to Pennsylvania, March 29, 1994; 24.
      - Senator Arlen Specter suggests discussion with Vice President Gore on Administration's proposed health care plan, March 31, 1994; 25.
      - Senator Specter will discuss what the Vice President does not want Pennsylvanians to know about the Clinton health care plan during a press conference on Thursday, March 31, at 9:30 am, March 31, 1994; 26.
      - Senator Specter and Mayor Tom Murphy meet to determine success of Pittsburgh gun task force at 202 Penn Circle West on Friday, April 1, at 9:00 am, April 1, 1994; 27.
      - Senator Specter wins additional funding for drug treatment programs, April 1, 1994; 28.
      - Senator Specter urges assistance from DEA and BATF to fight gang violence and drug traffic in Lancaster, April 1, 1994; 29.
      - Senator Specter praises retiring Supreme Court Justice Harry Blackmun, April 6, 1994; 30.
      - Senator Specter tours Philadelphia meat processing plant to review improvements in health and safety standards on Monday, April 11 at 9:30 am, April 11, 1994; 31.
      - Senator Specter salutes slain crew members of the U.S.S. Iowa in keynote at memorial service on April 16, at 2:00 pm, April 15, 1994; 32.
      - Memorial services for 47 U.S.S. Iowa crew members to be held at Philadelphia Naval Shipyard on Saturday, April 16, at 2:00 pm; Senator Arlen Specter to be keynote speaker, April 16, 1994; 33.
      - Senator Specter's bill to provide ERISA exemptions for states that provide prevailing rates for public works projects approved by Senate Labor Committee, April 14, 1994; 34.
      - Senator Specter hosts Republican Senators on Philadelphia retreat, April 15, 1994; 35.
      - Senator Specter responds to reports of two U.S. helicopters downed by friendly fire over Iraq, April 14, 1994; 36.
      - Memorial services for 47 U.S.S. Iowa crew members to be held at Philadelphia Naval Shipyard on Saturday, April 16, 2:00 pm; Senator Arlen Specter to be keynote speaker, April 16, 1994; 37.
      - Senator Specter salutes crewmembers of the U.S.S. Iowa in keynote at memorial service on April 16, 2:00 pm, April 15, 1994; 38.
      - Senator Specter to address teen pregnancy issues at the capitol annex building on Monday, April 18, at 11:15 am, April 18, 1994; 39.
      - Senator Arlen Specter mourns death of Pittsburgh councilman Duane Darkins, April 19, 1994; 40.
      - Senator Specter hosts cable TV "town meeting" to answer Pennsylvanians' questions on Bosnia, crime, and other issues, April 25, 1994; 41.
      - Senator Specter mourns death of President Nixon; He will attend funeral tomorrow in California, April 26, 1994; 42.
      - House and Senate budget committee conferees approve Senator Specter's amendment to restore full funding for LIHEAP, May 4, 1994; 43.
      - Senator Specter to examine implications of gene research with world-renowned experts at the University of Pennsylvania on Monday, May 9; press briefing to follow meetings at noon, May 9, 1994; 44.
      - Senator Specter introduces legislation to create a new bankruptcy judgeship for Eastern Pennsylvania District, May 12, 1994; 45.
      - Senator Specter responds to President Clinton's Supreme Court nominee Judge Stephen G. Breyer, May 13, 1994; 46.
      - Senator Specter meets with University of Pittsburgh breast cancer study administrators on steps being taken to ensure the integrity of federally-funded research projects, May 13, 1994; 47.
      - Senator Specter to announce multi-million dollar grant for gene research awarded to the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia by National Institutes of Health at 9:00 am, May 23, May 23, 1994; 48.
      - Supreme Court of United States reverses Navy Yard ruling; Senator Specter to respond at press conference today in Philadelphia, May 23, 1994; 49.
      - Senator Specter hosts cable TV "town meeting" to answer Pennsylvanians' questions on health care, crime, Philadelphia Naval Shipyard, and other issues, May 23, 1994; 50.
      - Senator Specter responds to Supreme Court ruling on base closures, May 23, 1994; 51.
      - Surgeon General Elders and Redskin Darrell Green will testify before Senator Specter during hearings on preventing growing rate of teenage pregnancies at 9:30 am, Wednesday, May 25, May 25, 1994; 52.
      - Senator Specter continues to fight against closing Philadelphia Naval Shipyard in letter to Defense Secretary Perry, May 26, 1994; 53.
      - Senator Specter solicits President Clinton's support for proposal to destroy Russian ships at Philadelphia Naval Shipyard, May 26, 1994; 54.
      - Senator Specter asks EPA to review emission guidelines affecting paper industry; request follows Senator's visit to Erie paper mill, May 26, 1994; 55.
      - Senator Specter to conduct hearings on preventing unwanted teenage pregnancies at 9:30 am, Wednesday, June 8, June 8, 1994; 56.
      - Senator Specter calls for investigation into gas pipeline explosion and urges additional funds for pipeline safety, June 13, 1994; 57.
      - Senators Specter, Shelby, and others form bipartisan monitoring group for Israeli-PLO peace accord, June 15, 1994; 58.
      - Senator Specter testifies in support of legislation he introduced to allow victims of terrorism in foreign countries to sue for damages, June 21, 1994; 59.
      - Senate committee approves legislation based on Senator Specter's bill allowing state to "just say no" to out-of-state trash, June 23, 1994; 60.
      - Senator Specter announces Department of Transportation grants to improve Pennsylvania airports, June 23, 1994; 61.
      - Senator Specter offers amendment to allow judicial review of fraudulent concealment in base closure process; effort follows up Supreme Court case on Philadelphia Naval Shipyard, June 23, 1994; 62.
      - Senator Specter to discuss funding for Pittsburgh gun task force and tour western Pennsylvania correctional facility on Monday, June 27 at 3:30 pm, June 27, 1994; 63.
      - Senator Specter hosts cable TV "town meeting" to answer Pennsylvanians' questions on health care, crime, and other issues, June 27, 1994; 64.
      - Senator Specter demands immediate action on busway expansion program for Pittsburgh International Airport at press conference on Monday, June 27 at 4:00 pm, June 27, 1994; 65.
      - Senator Specter to discuss funding for Pittsburgh Gun Task Force and tour western Pennsylvania correctional facility, June 27, 1994; 66.
      - Senator Specter announces Department of Transportation grants to improve Pennsylvania airports, June 28, 1994; 67.
      - Senate Appropriations Committee approves funding requests for Pennsylvania park sites at urging of Senator Specter, June 28, 1994; 68.
      - Senator Specter to meet with Supreme Court nominee Judge Stephen Breyer on Wednesday, June 29, at 3:00 pm, June 29, 1994; 69.
      - GAO reports that administrative cost estimate of Clinton health plan is not possible; study requested by Senator Specter finds numerous abnormalities in OMB estimates, June 29, 1994; 70.
      - Senator Specter announces $326,000 awarded in national service grants to seven Pennsylvania educational institutions, June 30, 1994; 71.
      - Senator Specter wins authorization for funds to build troop barracks for Fort Indiantown Gap National Guard facility, July 5, 1994; 72.
      - Senator Specter to discuss domestic violence prevention and tour YWCA shelter on Monday, July 11, at 11:45 am, July 11, 1994; 73.
      - Senator Specter to visit Gettysburg National Military Park on Monday, July 11 at 2:15 pm, July 11, 1994; 74.
      - Senator Specter to discuss domestic violence prevention and tour women's shelter on Monday, July 12, at 4:30 pm, July 12, 1994; 75.
      - Transportation subcommittee approves funding for Pennsylvania projects at the urging of Senator Specter, July 13, 1994; 76.
      - Senate approves amendment by Senator Specter to strengthen congressional review of the obligation of U.S. funds to the PLO, July 14, 1994; 77.
      - Senate Appropriations Committee approves construction funding for Fort Indiantown Gap National Guard facility at the urging of Senator Specter, July 14, 1994; 78.
      - Senator Specter, Mayor Rendell, and other announce legislation to revitalize America's cities at press conference in Philadelphia on Monday, July 18, at noon, July 18, 1994; 79.
      - Senator Specter urges extension of law allowing disclosure of JFK assassination documents, July 19, 1994; 80.
      - Appropriations subcommittee approves funding for LIHEAP at the urging of Senator Specter, July 20, 1994; 81.
      - Appropriations subcommittee approves funding for health care, education, and jobs at the urging of Senator Specter, July 20, 1994; 82.
      - Statement by Senator Specter on the death of Senator Hugh Scott, July 22, 1994; 83.
      - Senator Specter announces health care forums to be held on Monday, August 1, July 22, 1994; 84.
      - Senator Specter urges subcommittee funding for V-22 Osprey, July 25, 1994; 85.
      - Senator Specter receives U.S. Chamber of Commerce "Spirit of Enterprise" Award, July 26, 1994; 86.
      - Senate approves Senator Specter's amendments to test innovative education programs, July 28, 1994; 87.
      - Senate approves Senator Specter's amendment to educate young offenders, July 29, 1994; 88.
      - Crime conference committee approves full funding for police corps at the urging of Senator Specter, July 29, 1994; 89.
    - August-December 1994 (Box 1223, Folder 12)
      - Senator Specter to hold public health care forums in Pittsburgh, Harrisburg, and Philadelphia on Monday, August 1, August 1, 1994; 1.
      - Senator Specter to hold public health care forums via satellite due to votes called by the Senate majority leader Mitchell on Monday, August 1, August 1, 1994; 2.
      - Senator Specter and others to discuss bureaucracies created by most recent democratic health care plans in the Senate radio-TV gallery on Wednesday, August 10, at 11:30 am, August 10, 1994; 3.
      - Senate approves fiscal year 1995 labor, HHS, education bill; Senator Specter wins increased funding for teen pregnancy prevention and other health, education initiatives, August 10, 1994; 4.
      - Senate approves Senator Specter's amendments to defense appropriations bill; includes curtailing low-level training flights over central Pennsylvania, August 11, 1994; 5.
      - Senator Specter to meet with minority and women contractors about the construction of Philadelphia's new federal prison on Monday, August 15, August 15, 1994; 6.
      - Senator Specter urges review of appeals court decision which could require adjustment of 1990 census figures, August 15, 1994; 7.
      - Senator Specter issues statement regarding Senate action on the crime bill, August 25, 1994; 8.
      - Senator Specter and Mayor Tom Murphy to meet with Pittsburgh Cultural Trust officials about the revitalization of America's cities at press conference on Thursday, September 8, at 9:00 am, September 8, 1994; 9.
      - Senator Specter to discuss benefits of crime package at news conference in Philadelphia, Friday, September 9, at 9:30 am, September 9, 1994; 10.
      - Senator Specter tells President Clinton on his strong objections to an invasion of Haiti, September 9, 1994; 11.
      - Senator Specter to discuss health care reform with doctors, nurses, and health care providers at press conference in Allentown on Thursday, September 11, at 4:15 pm, September 11, 1994; 12.
      - Senator Specter responds to President Clinton's remarks about the possible invasion of Haiti, September 15, 1994; 13.
      - Senator Specter comments on recent developments in Haiti, September 19, 1994; 14.
      - Senator Specter announces federal funding for Gettysburg National Military Park approved today by the Senate Appropriations Committee, September 22, 1994; 15.
      - Senate Appropriations Committee funds Pittsburgh busway expansion program urged by Senator Specter, September 22, 1994; 16.
      - Senator Specter urges administration to oppose adjustment of 1990 census figures, September 26, 1994; 17.
      - Senator Specter announces additional funds from Senate Appropriations Committee for Pittsburgh busway expansion program, September 27, 1994; 18.
      - Senator Specter to address Planned Parenthood; calls for removal of anti-abortion plank from Republican Party platform on Thursday, September 29, at 10:00 am, September 28, 1994; 19.
      - Senator Specter announces Judiciary Committee approval of legislation to allow victims of terrorism in foreign countries to sue for damages, September 28, 1994; 20.
      - Senator Specter announces U.S. Department of Agriculture grant to improve health care delivery in rural Pennsylvania, September 30, 1994; 21.
      - Senator Specter announces approval of legislation to stop the flow of interstate trash into Pennsylvania, September 30, 1994; 22.
      - Senator Specter announces full funding for Pittsburgh Gun Task Force, October 4, 1994; 23.
      - Senator Specter receives National Security Leadership Award for voting record on issues of defense and foreign policy, October 5, 1994; 24.
      - Senator Specter announces Senate approval of the "Improving America's Schools Act," including programs to improve prenatal education, educate youth offenders, and encourage innovative school reform, October 5, 1994; 25.
      - Senator Specter introduces legislation to inspire rebirth of America's cities; new urban agenda would revitalize cities as nation's economic growth centers, October 7, 1994; 26.
      - Senator Specter to meet with teens at Letsche Education Center, 1350 Cliff Street on Monday, October 17, at 10:00 am, October 17, 1994; 27.
      - Senator Specter urges religious tolerance in speech to ADL National Executive Committee in Los Angeles on October 21, 12:30 pm PDT, October 21, 1994; 28.
      - Senator Specter announces $199,000 grant by Justice Department to fully fund the Pittsburgh Gun Task Force, October 26, 1994; 29.
      - Senator Specter urges PLO leader Yasser Arafat to condemn recent terrorist attacks against Israel, October 28, 1994; 30.
      - Senator Specter urges passage of GATT, November 30, 1994; 31.
      - Senator Specter to attend government symposium at University of Pennsylvania on Wednesday, December 14, at 2:00 pm, December 14, 1994; 32.
      - Senator Specter responds to President's remarks on tax cuts, December 15, 1994; 33.